Partition on a strange madness!
Clean, Shaven is a drama, crime, thriller film directed by Lodge Kerrigan.
Peter Winter is a young schizophrenic who is desperately trying to
get his daughter back from her adoptive family.
He attempts to function in a world that, for him, is filled with strange voices,
electrical noise, disconcerting images, and jarringly sudden emotional shifts.
During his quest, he runs afoul of the law and an ongoing murder investigation.
Peter Winter, played by Peter Greene.
Jack McNally, played by Robert Albert.
Mrs. Winter, played by Megan Owen.
Nicole Winter, played by Jennifer MacDonald.
Melinda Frayne, played by Molly Castelloe.
Dr. Michaels, played by J. Dixon Byrne.
Clean, Shaven is a 1993 drama film written, produced and directed by Lodge Kerrigan, in which Peter Winter (played by Peter
Greene) is a man with schizophrenia desperately trying to get his daughter back from her adoptive mother.
The film attempts to subjectively view schizophrenia
and those who are affected by it.
At the 1993 Chicago Film Festival, the film won the
Silver Hugo Award for Best First Feature.
The film was screened in the Un Certain Regard section and nominated for
the Caméra d'Or award at the 1994 Cannes Film Festival.
Clean, Shaven was made a part of The Criterion Collection in 2006.
The film explores themes of daughter, beach,
schizophrenia, obsession, detective.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional and intense.